<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
<channel>
<title>Transit Radio</title>
<link>http://www.transitradio.no</link>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>2016 Transnational Arts Production</copyright>
<itunes:subtitle>A podcast radio station recorded at reception centers for asylum Seekers in Norway</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:author>Transnational Arts Production</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary>Transit Radio is a podcast radio station recorded at reception centers for asylum Seekers in Norway. The recordings are from workshops with asylum-seekers led by professional musicians. In addition there will be interviews with asylum seekers about what music they play while in transit and about what it means to them.</itunes:summary>
<description>The recordings are from workshops with asylum-seekers led by professional musicians. In addition there will be interviews with asylum seekers about what music they play while in transit and about what it means to them.</description>
<itunes:owner>
<itunes:name>Transit Radio</itunes:name>
<itunes:email>post@transitradio.no</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/tr-podcast-cover.png"/>
<itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics">
</itunes:category>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<item>
<title>Episode 1: Karlstad</title>
<itunes:author>Sofia Bagge, Khaled Harara, Abazar A. Bagi Hamid, Sheldon George Blackman, Hilde Ghosh Maisey</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Khaled Harara and Monirah Hashemi's Workshops.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>The first episode visits the workshops done by Khaled Harara and Monirah Hashemi to empower young refugees in Karlstad, Sweden.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-1/tr-episode-1.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5190287" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-1/tr-episode-1.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-1/tr-episode-1.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>10:55</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 2: Harstad</title>
<itunes:author>Peter Daatland, Abazar A. Bagi Hamid, Rafiq, Mohammed</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Harstad, Mohammed and Rafiq.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In episode 2 of Transit Radio you will get to hear the voice of «Mohammed» and «Rafiq», who have fled from, and with music. In addition you´ll also meet Abazar Hamid who left his band Agd Elgalad, the self-proclaimed «the Beatles of Sudan» behind, and is now leading music workshops under the protection of Safemuse.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-2/tr-episode-2.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5953797" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-2/tr-episode-2.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-2/tr-episode-2.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>13:01</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 3: Tromso</title>
<itunes:author>Sofia Bagge, Nasra Omar</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Music is identity. Music is memory.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In episode 3 of Transit Radio you get to meet percussionist Nasra Omar who started a project with the simple idea that people can meet and bond with the help of music, even though the resources are scarce. You’ll also meet a young girl, dreaming of the opportunity to dance.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-3/tr-episode-3.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5199100" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-3/tr-episode-3.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-3/tr-episode-3.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>11:12</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 4: Oslo World Music Festival</title>
<itunes:author>Anne Gerd Grimsby Haarr, Mahsa Vahdat</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Oslo World Music Festival</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In episode 4 of Transit Radio you will get to hear the voice of Mahsa Vahdat a couple of days before her performance at the Oslo World Music Festival. She is an acclaimed iranian artist and singer who has an audience all over the world, but is not allowed to sing in her own country.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-4/tr-episode-4.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5471271" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-4/tr-episode-4.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-4/tr-episode-4.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 2 Nov 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>11:27</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 5: Hvalstad</title>
<itunes:author>Sofia Bagge</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>We share the music that is important to us.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>The kids here are a lot more attached and observant to the lyrics. I don’t think a lot of Norwegian kids care that much about that. They know them, but they don’t care or understand what the lyrics are about. During a long and often dangerous road for refugees, the mobile phone is vital for navigating borders and getting the information that you need. But can it also be a way to connect you to your memories? In episode 5 of Transit Radio you will meet some of the teenagers living at the Hvalstad transit center, just outside of Oslo. Being far away from home, alone in a foreign country, they share the music that is important to them.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-5/tr-episode-5.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="6222879" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-5/tr-episode-5.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-5/tr-episode-5.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 9 Nov 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>13:34</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 6: Kveldskoret</title>
<itunes:author>Cathrine Hasselberg</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Just like people cross borders, so does music.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>Just like people cross borders, so does music. And for many people, music is a key component of their lives. In episode 6 of Transit Radio you will meet Abigail and Felix who both sing in a choir in Levanger called Kveldskoret. Over two cold November evenings Kveldskoret was joined by Sheldon Blackman and the soul rebels for the purpose of coming together and make music flow across linguistic and cultural borders.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-6/tr-episode-6.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="4567318" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-6/tr-episode-6.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-6/tr-episode-6.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>10:18</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 7: Grimstad</title>
<itunes:author>Anne Gerd Grimsby Haarr</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Before the Syrian revolution started, I played. But after that (…) it was very difficult to play with the oud, with the music or anything.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In episode 7 of Transit Radio you will meet two artists, both new in Norway but with very different stories. Zia Mushini came alone from Afghanistan as a refugee. After only singing by himself his whole childhood he suddenly finds himself in the start of a hip hop career. Hassan Al-Mustafa is blind and was a famous artist in Syria when growing up. When war broke out in his country there was no time for playing anymore and he left to Norway. Will music return to his life?</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-7/tr-episode-7.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="6237642" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-7/tr-episode-7.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-7/tr-episode-7.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 1 Dec 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>12:51</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 8: Torshov</title>
<itunes:author>Peter Daatland</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>A person cannot not eat, sleep, eat, sleep. He will be sick.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In Torshov Transittmottak in Oslo asylum seekers stay for only a few weeks, waiting for their interview which will decide whether they may stay or not. A lot of waiting, in a limbo between a clear past and a blurry future. But how do they keep the spirit up through the waiting time? Listening to music.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-8/tr-episode-8.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5557916" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-8/tr-episode-8.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-8/tr-episode-8.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 7 Dec 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>11:51</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 9: Harstad</title>
<itunes:author>Anne Gerd Grimsby Haarr</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Somebody is coming, somebody is leaving</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>In Harstad city there is a choir called Hope, with members from the local community together with newly arrived refugees. They have shared lullabies from their different countries to record them in a studio. The personal and emotional experience of singing some of the most beautiful words they know, meets a huge contrast when politics makes a different ending to this story.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-9/tr-episode-9.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="6303491" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-9/tr-episode-9.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-9/tr-episode-9.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>13:14</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
<item>
<title>Episode 10: Hybrid</title>
<itunes:author>Cathrine Hasselberg</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>If you don´t listen to music, I feel like you are not human</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:summary>n this final episode of transit radio you will meet Vasuky Jayapalan and some of her students as they rehearse and learn more about Tamil music and culture. Vasuky Jayapalan came to Norway in 1991 and spent 12 years learning and understanding the Norwegian system for working within the cultures, all to bring her Tamil background to a larger audience. She has released several CD´s and played large concerts both as a solo artist and in collaboration with other artists. With her extensive background in music she now works to bridge the Tamil and Norwegian culture, teaching traditional music, dance and arts to her students. But has music changed for her since settling down in a new country? What does music mean to her now, and what purpose does it serve?</itunes:summary>
<itunes:image href="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-10/tr-episode-10.jpg"/>
<enclosure length="5813338" type="audio/x-m4a" url="http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-10/tr-episode-10.m4a"/>
<guid>http://www.transitradio.no/podcasts/episode-10/tr-episode-10.m4a</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>12:55</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
